Gerhard Molin

Product Strategist (Freelancer) Helsinki, Finland

T: +358 45 220 3414

E: gerhard@minimumbadass.com

P: gerhardmolin.strikingly.com

Summary

Being a human-centered designer I push for customer-centric solutions. I am radically inspired by people and show create empathy for the user. In the design research I use qualitative research (eg by organising fieldwork, facilitating co-creation sessions, conducting contextual interviews, performing usability studies, etc.). I interpret and translate rich user insights towards a clear vision for innovative products, services, spaces, interactions and experiences. I test early prototypes iteratively with users to move ideas closer to market launch.

Publications

The Role of the Teacher in Game-Based Learning: A Review and Outlook

Towards a Teacher-Culture of Participation

Top Skills

Entrepreneurship

UX Design

Product Strategy

Experience



Product Strategist

Freelancer, Helsinki, Finland

01/2019 - Present

As freelance product strategist I help startups to shorten the time between idea and learning in order to learn fast and early to move forward. I help my clients with Growth Hacking (Growth Design Sprints), User Experience Design, Lean Startup Experiment Design, 4-Day Design Sprints, Lightning Decision Jams, User Research, Rapid Prototyping and Usability Testing

Design Strategist

09/2018 - 02/2019

Polkuni, Helsinki, Finland

Polkuni is a Helsinki and Hong Kong based hands-on investment and activation company. I helped Polkuni's portfolio startups with Business Design, UX Research, Designing & Executing Lean Startup Experiments and 4-Day Design Sprints.

CEO. Co-Founder

09/2016-09/2018

Unserious, Helsinki, Finland

Our mission was to design phyiscal games that unleash people's creativity and bring them togther. Our award winning board game LUPO: The Space Adventure was sold out in UK & USA over Amazon, exceeding lifetime industry average sales in just a few months. We raised \$120k in risk capital and generated \$70k in revenue within 8 months of founding the company. My primary tasks at Unserious as CEO / Co-founder included Game Gesign, UX Design, UX Research, Rapid Prototyping, Planning and Executing Experiments (Lean Startup Methodology), Pitching, Fundraising and Sales.

PhD Design Researcher

01/2016-09/2016

University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland

At the University of Helsinki I continued where I left off at RMIT. My focus has been to create creative and playful tools that empower teachers as (game) designers of their classroom. I published one book chapter "The Role of the Teacher in Game- Based Learning" (Springer) and one conference workshop paper "Towards a Teacher-Culture of Participation". It was during that time when the idea for the creative and ridiculous storytelling game LUPO: The Space Adventure emerged.

Education

| University of Helsinki PhD in Education, Helsinki, Finland | 2016-Present |
|---|--------------|
| RMIT PhD in Creative Media, Melbouren, Australia | 2015–2015 |
| Brunel University MA in Digital Game Theory & Design, London, UK | 2013–2014 |

Vienna University of Business and Economics

2009-2013

BSc, Vienna, Austria